PROFESSOR: So now we're going to talk
about what exactly is this object
mathematically, and what are some
algorithms for solving this problem
that we've formulated?
And one nice thing is there's
this line here.
You formulate the search problem, and
that's very problem specific.
And then you solve it.
Solving the search problem does not
actually require knowledge of whether
or not there are power pellets
or how they work.
All that's encoded in an abstracted
way in the start state and the
successor function, and so on.
So all our algorithms for solution are
going to reference things like the
successor function and the goal test,
not things like scared timers.
All right.
So what is a state space?
Well, it's basically a graph.
And we can draw this state space
graph, which is a mathematical
representation of our search problem.
So for the case of Pac-Man eating dots,
it might look like this, right?
There's a bunch of different states you
can be in, and they're connected
by actions.
These actions have labels,
north, south, east, and
west that I've omitted.
This graph is quite big, even for a
modest size board, because different
dot configurations for this search
problem are different.
And so here's a very large
search state space graph.
The nodes are going to be some
abstraction of world configurations.
The more you can abstract, all else
equal, the more efficient
your search will be.
The arcs represent the successors, so
the successor function here is encoded
in the arts.
From any given state, my successor
function returns my neighbors in the
graph in a directed sense.
The goal test isn't shown
in the graph, right?
Graphs have nodes and arcs, and
weights and things like that.
The goal test isn't shown
on the graph.
It's another thing you have to get to
have a search problem, and it's a set
of goal nodes, or a function over goal
nodes that tell you when you're done.
Similarly, you need to know the start.
So an important point that will become
more important and confusable later.
In this search graph, each
state occurs only once.
So for example, let's say this
is your start state here.
And let's say we're considering
this state here.
There are a couple ways to get there.
Actually, for this state up here there
are kind of infinitely many ways to
get there, right?
Just walk back and forth.
OK, there are a lot of different ways to
get to these states, but the state
occurs only once in this graph.
Very, very critical distinction.
In a search graph, each state occurs
once, regardless of the number of
paths through the graph
that can get to it.
In general, this graph is a
nice mathematical object.
We can think about it, but
we don't build it, right?
Because it's exponentially big.
We try to avoid building things
that are exponentially big.
And in general we can't build it, we
can't fit it in memory, we don't have
enough time to build it.
It's a useful idea, but
it is just an idea.
We don't actually build the whole thing
and then search it, for example.
For the purposes of this lecture next,
we're going to be playing with this
tiny little search problem.
When you see a search problem that fits
on a PowerPoint slide, in general
you should laugh inside at the tiny
little funny search problem.
Because a real search problem never
fits on a PowerPoint slide.
If they were like this, there
would be no lecture here.
It would be just enumerate everything
and whatever, right?
The idea is we have this graph, and
we'd like to somehow find paths in
this graph, optimal solutions without
ever writing most of the graph down.
That's the trick.
So what do we do?
Well, we don't want to write down the
whole graph, because most of it's not
relevant to us.
What is relevant to us?
The start state's relevant to us, and
the things that can happen from here
are relevant to us.
So the object that we work with is
what's called a search tree.
And this object will
also have problems.
What is a search tree?
Well, at the top of the tree
is the current state.
This is now.
This is the start state.
What can happen next?
Well, we have our actions, and below
that we have possible futures.
Right below the start state is what can
happen in one step, and that just
continues on down.
And the deeper you go, you're just
traveling into the future.
It's like science fiction.
So this is essentially
the tree of what if.
Every plan you could possibly execute
is in this tree somewhere.
The start state is the root.
Children correspond to successors.
Each node in this graph has a state
that it corresponds to.
But it's really a plan.
So this node here, although it looks
a lot like this search state, it's
actually more than that.
It's the plan of being in the
start state and going north,
and ending up there.
There are other ways
to end up in this.
For example, you could go north and then
south and then north, and that's
down here somewhere.
It has the same state, but it's
elsewhere in the tree, because nodes
in this tree correspond
to plans, not states.
Critical distinction.
Again, I told you we don't
build the graph.
Well, we don't build the tree either.
Tree is at least as bad as the graph.
So what's the point?
The point is, we try to just build a
tiny little piece of this tree, and we
try to have algorithms that guarantee we
did the right thing even though we
ignored most of the tree.
That's going to be the tree.